motorbikewriter.com 2019-04-18

# Privacy & Security - Motorbike Writer

We take both privacy & security very seriously indeed; this section provides information on key points relating to our privacy and security policies.

If you find anything unclear or if you have suggestions on how we might make anything clearer, we would like to receive your feedback. Please email: [info@motorbikewriter.com](mailto:info@motorbikewriter.com).

We adhere to Australian data protection legislation (often referred to as the ‘Privacy Acts’).

We only take information from you which is reasonably necessary for our business functions and we provide information below about each of the following specific areas:

  * What data we collect.
  * How we collect your data.
  * How we use your data.
  * How we will communicate with you.
  * How you can access your information.
  * Our cookie policy.

## What data we collect

The personal information we collect from you is what is reasonably necessary for our business functions.

We may collect the following types of personal information:

**Identifying and communicating with you:**

  * First/Last Name
  * Gender
  * eMail address
  * Phone number

**Shipping address/Billing address including:**

  * House number/Name
  * Post/zip code
  * City
  * State
  * Country
  * Timemzone

**Payment Details**

Please note that we do not store your payment details. We use a reputable third-party payment provider called Stripe.

You can select for Stripe to store your payment details securely for future transactions, although you will be required to authenticate all payments.

For more information please see [Stripe’s privacy policy](https://stripe.com/au/privacy).

## How we collect your data

We collect information from you directly and explicitly via data collection forms used in three main interactions:

  1. Newsletter sign-up
  2. Site surveys (excluding polls where no personal information is collected)
  3. Orders placed via the shop

Please note that if you send us personal information that we have not requested, or we determine that the personal information you have provided to us is not reasonably necessary or directly related to any of our business functions or activities, we may delete this information without notifying you to protect your privacy.

**Please do not post any personal information or payment/transaction information to us in public forums or social media platforms.**

**We will never ask you to send us any payment details via email or confirm or login via links embedded within emails. Remain vigilant to** **[scams](https://www.scamwatch.gov.au/types-of-scams) and find more information about ****[phishing here](https://www.scamwatch.gov.au/types-of-scams/attempts-to-gain-your-personal-information/phishing)** **.**

Only communicate with us by emailing either [info@motorbikewriter.com](mailto:info@motorbikewriter.com) for general enquiries or [shop@motorbikewriter.com](mailto:shop@motorbikewriter.com) for order-related enquiries.

## How we use your data

We use your data in accordance with the terms provided at the point of data collection. This means that for the newsletter we will use your email and or name for personalising the email you are sent and, in some cases, postcode where targeting Geo location limited offers and promotions.

We will not send you newsletter or promotional emails where you expressly opt out of receiving either.

We use your name/address and payment details to process and fulfil orders and receive payments where you place an order with us. Please note that where you place an order with us for a product supplied by a third party we may share relevant details with them to enable them to process and delivery your order.

## How we will communicate with you

We may send you direct marketing communications and information about products and services offered by us or our partners or suppliers via the channels you have nominated on submission. This may include, but is not limited to, email, SMS, regular mail, social media and other digital channels.

If you have indicated a preference for a method of communication, we will endeavour to use that method wherever practical to do so.

You may opt out of receiving marketing communications at any time by responding via the channel in which you received the marketing communication, or by contacting us at [info@motorbikewriter.com](mailto:info@motorbikewriter.com).

You can unsubscribe from newsletter emails by clicking the “unsubscribe” link on the footer of the email communication you have received.

## How you can access your information

You may access your personal information (where it is held online) by logging into [my account](http://motorbikewriter.com/shop/my-account/) on the website.

You may also access your personal information held by Motorbike Writer by making a request to us at [info@motorbikewriter.com](mailto:info@motorbikewriter.com).

Normally we will provide a record of your personal information to you via phone or email and may charge an admin fee where call charges apply. Please note that we will not disclose any information relating to payment details.

If your request is unlawful or may interfere with the privacy of others we may reasonably refuse to provide access to your personal information.

If you would like us to update or amend your personal information, please contact us and we will make the requested amendments.

We may ask you to verify your identity to ensure that personal information we hold is not improperly accessed.

Change privacy settings

## Our Cookie Policy

At Motorbike Writer we use a number of cookies on our sites. We use cookies to enable us to provide visitors with the best customer experience possible while navigating our sites. By using our site, visitors implicitly agree to our use of cookies.

We take the privacy of our customers and the visitors to our site very seriously. If you want to know more about cookie management, we have provided below an explanation and links to more information on how you can manage cookies in your browser.

We provide specific details about the cookies we use and the reasons for using these cookies to enable site visitors to make an informed decision and thus provide informed consent.

If you don’t want to dig into the details, then our high-level reasons for using cookies might provide you with enough information to continue happily using our site. They include:

  * Enabling key site functionality
  * Measuring & testing user behaviour on our sites
  * Driving customer understanding to improve our site & customer experience
  * Improving the targeting and relevance of sales & marketing communications

For details on the cookies we use across Motorbike Writer sites and why we use them please read below:

### What are Cookies?

The use of Cookies and similar technologies has for some time been commonplace and cookies in particular are important in the provision of many online services.

### Cookie scope – Session Vs Persistent Cookies

Cookies can expire at the end of a browser session (from when a user opens the browser window to when they exit the browser) or they can be stored for longer.

_Session cookies_  – Allow websites to link the actions of a user during a browser session. They may be used for a variety of purposes such as remembering what a user has put in their shopping basket as they browse around a site. They could also be used for security when a user is accessing internet banking or to facilitate use of webmail. These session cookies expire after a browser session so would not be stored long term. For this reason, session cookies may sometimes be considered less privacy intrusive than persistent cookies.

_Persistent cookies_  – Are stored on a user’s device in between browser sessions which allows the preferences or actions of the user across a site (or in some cases across different websites) to be remembered. Persistent cookies may be used for a variety of purposes including remembering a user’s preferences and choices when using a site or to target advertising.

### Cookie Sources – First Vs Third Party

Whether a cookie is ‘first’ or ‘third’ party refers to the website or domain placing the cookie.

First party cookies in basic terms are cookies set by a website visited by the user – the website displayed in the URL window.

Third party cookies are cookies that are set by a domain other than the one being visited by the user. If a user visits a website and a separate company sets a cookie through that website this would be a third party cookie.

### Managing Cookies

You can control what cookies can be set on your computer. For more information on specific requirements please refer to your web browser help file or for more information please check [here](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/).

### What Cookies are used on our sites and why do we use them?

The following list provides a comprehensive overview of the Cookies used on our site and what tool or technology each is used for and why we are using each tool.

This list includes cookies deployed by third parties on our websites. By using the Motorbike Writer website, mobile website or Apps, you are agreeing to our T&Cs, Privacy and Cookie policies and consent to the use of cookies and similar technologies by us and our carefully selected third party partners as described in these policies.

If you do not agree to such use, please see the Managing Cookies section for details on how to adjust your settings.

We will update this list as we make changes to the shopping experience on our websites, mobile website and mobile applications.

List of cookie based technologies that we use on the site:

  1. Functional/Optimisation of site content

  * Google Analytics & GTM – Website analytics tracking to monitor and optimise the website content performance and user clickstream behaviour
  * Mail Chimp – Our Email platform used to send the newsletter
  * ShareThis – Social sharing functionality
  * WordPress – The content management system (CMS) that the site is hosted on
  * Woo Commerce – Site shop technology

  2. Advertising-related technology

  * Adroll
  * Affectv
  * Aggregate knowledge
  * Appnexus
  * BlueKai
  * DoubleClick
  * DoubleClick for Publishers (DFP)
  * Google Adsense
  * Integral Ad Science
  * Moat
  * Quantcast
  * RocketFuel

## Security

We use industry standard security measures to safeguard and protect your information. This includes taking reasonable steps to ensure your personal information is protected from misuse, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

You should remain vigilant to ensure that your systems/devices are safe and secure using up-to-date anti-virus and anti-spyware software, and a good firewall. Only buy computer and anti-virus software from a reputable source. [For more information on hacking threats click here](https://www.scamwatch.gov.au/types-of-scams/attempts-to-gain-your-personal-information/hacking).

If you have any questions about privacy & security which you would like more information on then please email [info@motorbikewriter.com](mailto:info@motorbikewriter.com).
